Guide to the Nicholas School of the Environment's Senior Professional Program Records, 1977-1997
Duke University. University Archives
- Accession UA 1997-0072, 1993-1994, (2 boxes)
  - Land Conservation Strategies--Ludington; syllabus, correspondence with instructor, 1994 Fall, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Aquatic Ecological Risk Assessment: Methods and Applications--Di Giulio/Parkhurst/Warren-Hicks; syllabus, correspondence with instructor, 1994 Fall, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Reporting the Results of Forestland Appraisals--Sizemore/Baldwin; syllabus, correspondence with instructor, 1994 Fall, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Environmental Advocacy and Its Tools--Painter/Watts; correspondence with instructor, instructor evaluations, 1994 Fall, (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Accession UA 1999-0081, 1990-1997, (4 boxes)
  Syllabi, correspondence with instructors and participants, printed matter, and other materials offered in intensive courses from 1990-1997, as part of either the Continuing Education Program or the Center for Environmental Education. Arranged as received; all folders are syllabi unless otherwise described.
  [Restricted until 2022]
  - Financial Management--Master Copy, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Preparing and Documenting Environmental Impact Analyses, 1996 Dec. 2-6 and 1997 Apr. 28-May 2, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Medicine for the Third World Traveler, 1995 Oct. 26-29 and 1996 Oct. 24-27, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Dynamic Modeling, 1992 Fall (Box 4)
  - Implementation of the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA), 1994, 1995 and 1996, (7 folders) (Box 4)
  - Negotiation Skills for Settling Public Disputes, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Watershed Management for Water Supply Protection, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Land Conservation Strategies, 1994, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Hazardous Waste Management: Regulations, Policies, and Implementation (RCRA), 1990 Oct., (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - New Advances in Ecological Risk Assessment, 1997 Mar. 24-27, (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Environmental Toxicology and Risk Assessment, 1993 Mar. 29-Apr. 2, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Medicine for the Third World Traveler, 1994 Oct. 27-30 and 1997 Oct., (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Implementation of the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) on Federal Land and Facilities, 1995 May 1-5, 1996 Dec. 9-13, and 1997 Apr.21-25, (6 folders) (Box 5)
  - Conservation Land Acquisition, 1992 Nov. 16-20, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - New Advances in Ecological Risk Assessment, 1996 Feb. 20-23 (Box 6)
  - Conservation Land Acquisition--course materials, 1992 Nov. 16-20 (Box 6)
  - Conservation Land Acquisition: Connecting Florida's Communities for Florida's Future--course workbook, 1992 Nov. 20 (Box 6)
  - Appraisal for Conservation Land Acquisition, 1992 Nov. (Box 6)
  - Basic Ground-Water Hydrology, 1994 Mar. 14-18 (Box 6)
  - Applied Groundwater Hydraulics, 1995 Dec. 7-8 (Box 6)
  - Implementation of NEPA, 1994 Spring, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Environmental Planning and Land Development, 1993 Mar. 8-12, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Basic Ground-Water Hydrology, 1995 Feb. 27- Mar. 3 (Box 6)
  - Army National Guard NEPA Course, 1994 Nov. 15-19, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Preparing and Documenting Environmental Impact Analyses, 1996 Apr. 1-5 (Box 6)
  - Elements of Forestry, 1990 Mar. 5-9 (Box 6)
  - Models for Landscape Forestry: meeting Consumer Demands, 1994 Oct. 3-7 (Box 6)
  - Forest Appraisal I and II, 1993 Feb.-1993 Spring, (Folders 1-3 of 5) (Box 6)
    Includes multiple offerings of the courses Forest Appraisal I and II between February 1993 and Spring 1993. Materials include student handbooks, syllabi, and sample appraisal. Arranged chronologically.
  - Forest Appraisal I and II, 1993 Feb.-1993 Spring, (Folders 4-5 of 5) (Box 7)
  - Forest Appraisal, 1993 Aug.-1996 June, (15 folders) (Box 7)
    Includes multiple offerings of the courses Reporting the Results of Forestland Appraisals, Forest Appraisals, Forest Appraisals I and Forest Appraisals II. Materials include student handbooks, course materials, sample appraisal. Courses offered at both Duke University and in Portland, Ore. Arranged chronologically.